UX UI PRODUCT DESIGNER | VISUAL DESIGNER **INFO-ARCHITECTURE | ILLUSTRATIONS** 



9'd love to hear from you!

New Jersey, USA



victoria@curlydesigner.com



in https://www.linkedin.com/in/curlydesigner/

Immersed in a rich palette of creativity & deep understanding of design principles & human-centered design. I have been breaking down complex design challenges into intuitive experiences - ensuring the result is highly functional, visually appealing, accessible, and meets product objectives. My design journey has been enriched not only by exploration and discovery but also through teaching and hands-on, holistic experience across the entire product life-cycle from concept to launch, working in both B2B and B2C sectors.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Research UX/UI Design   Instructional & eLearning Online Education & Webinars	02/2024 - 06/2024
Sr UX/UI Product Designer Warner Bros Discovery	08/2022 - 10/2023
Senior UX/UI   Visual Designer   eLearning Hatch Early Child Education	04/2022 - 07/2022
Senior UX/UI Product Designer & Visual BlackBerry Cyber Security	01/2017 - 10/2021
UX/UI Product Design & Architecture Scotia Bank	10/2016 - 12/2016
UX/UI Research   Visual Design & Video Editing Compass Group	01/2016 - 04/2016
UI Interactive Designer & Illustrator Wizits Ltd Game Studio	01/2014 - 07/2014
Interactive Digital Designer & Illustraor	09/2012 - 03/2013

### **VOLUNTEERING**

BWIN Party Digital Media and Entertainment

Art Teacher Assistant	
GRTW Academy, NJ, US	

### Photography & Videography Tamarak, NJ, US

Instructional Designer UX/UI Course Development.

Sheridon College, ON, CA

Professor Assistant

**Teaching Design Tools** London Middlesex University London, UK

### **DESIGN TOOLS**

Product Design	Illustrations & Graphics	Video, Sound & Animation
Adobe XD Figma Sketch Zeplin Miro	Adobe Creative Illustrator Photoshop InDesign Afinity Designer	After Effects Premiere Pro Final Cut Pro Adobe Animate
3D Design		Web
Autodesk 3D Max Cinema 4D Autodesk Revit Blender		GitHub/ Code Markdown Wordpress HTML CSS Confluence

### **EDUCATION**



### MA DESIGN FOR INTERACTIVE MEDIA

London Middlesex University



## **B.DESIGN** INTERIOR ARCHITECTURE **& 3D ENVIRONMENTS**

The College of Management -School of Design

### **COURSES & TRAINING**

### **LEADERSHIP**

- UX Management (HECMontrealX)
- · Product Leadership (USMx)

#### **PRODUCT & BUSINESS COURSES:**

- Cyber Security
- Data-Driven Product Research & **Design Thinking**
- Product Management for AI Udemy

### **ART DESIGN & ARCHITECTURE**

- · Design Thinking for UX Design Leaders
- · Research & System Thinking for Product Design

MDX University

- · Human Interaction, Consumer Behavior & Social Pscychology
- · Phylosophy History of Art Design & Architecture
- · Narrative, Cinema and Game Set Design

The College of Management

#### **TECHNICAL COURSES:**

- · HTML/CSS, Markdown, CMS
- · Animation, Video and Effects
- · 3D Design Modeling & Rendering

MDX University

### **EXPERIENCE DESCRIPTION**



## Research UX/UI Design | Instructional & eLearning

Online Education & Webinars

| 02/2024 - 06/2024

- Design and implement materials for comprehensive lesson plans and instructional materials tailored to accommodate learners from diverse backgrounds and varying levels of expertise.
- Taking part in a webinar to Introduce a course that involves the theory of Design principles, UX research methodologies & user-centered design solutions.
- Mentor students at different levels of their creative journey. Guiding ideation, design thinking processes, visual communication, design systems, typography, color theory, and layout.



## Sr UX/UI Product Designer

Warner Bros Discovery

1 08/2022 - 10/2023

- Collaborate with cross-functional team members like Product Managers, Researchers, Content Strategists, and Engineers to gather
  information, conduct competitor research & analyze user behavior and visual challenges. Understand the technical requirements and
  limitations, customers/stakeholders needs, business requirements, and technologies. Use my design thinking to consider company values
  and find creative solutions that work, both for the product and the brand.
- Applying human-centered design implementation to focus on intuitive functionality and developing a unified Design System. Create
  components to ensure a cohesive & user-friendly experience throughout the product ecosystem. Produce user flows, info-architecture,
  wireframes, mockups, and prototypes to enhance overall user experience. Design user-friendly and visually appealing features and
  components that contribute to the product's improvement.
- Document core functionality and guidelines recommendations in Figma, Miro & Confluence for team reference. Establishing a shared understanding of design principles and guidelines, fostering an organized workflow for seamless integration across diverse teams.
- Support the Engineering team & test the implemented designs while ensuring user accessibility is maintained. Coordinate between teams,
  effectively bridging communication gaps and enhancing collaboration.
- · Participate in user testing sessions to gather insights and leverage user feedback to enhance the design.



## Senior UX/UI | Visual Designer | eLearning

Hatch Early Child Education

| 04/2022 - 07/2022

- Supporting the ongoing evolution and merger of multiple e-learning products into one Brand. Evolving design language and creating a Brand Identity & enhancing the user experience across all products to help create friendly interactions and intuitive experiences.
- Maintaining design system components to ensure consistency. Support discussions with engineering to ensure a common understanding
  of the outcomes. Sharing feedback and design recommendations to help create friendly interactions and intuitive experiences.



# Senior UX/UI Product Designer & Visual

BlackBerry Cyber Security

| 01/2017 - 10/202

- Multichannel Collaboration Worked across different channels in the company: designing for IoT, Cybersecurity Privacy, Productivity, and Gamification
- Holistic Considerations for human factors, user research/ usability, and accessibility throughout the design process. Creating user-centered
  and intuitive Design solutions to simplify complex data structures & optimize user workflows. Including responsive web & mobile (IOS/
  Android) for customer-facing platforms and applications. Considering accessibility & ensuring a cohesive experience across various devices
  and platforms
- Ensuring a consistent & delightful user experience while considering platform-specific design guidelines and maintaining a unified brand identity.
- Comprehensive Design considerations from information architecture, user flows, wireframes, UI components, infographics, and data visualizations.
- Leading a Design System for a comprehensive dark vs light theme background across all products. Conducting case studies & research to
  address challenges related to dark & light theme usage. Developed design system guidelines for accessibility and visual aesthetics in both
  dark and light backgrounds.
- Crafted a tailored experience for first-time users, including intro screens, empty-data visualization, infographics & iconography with a tutorial and helpful tool-tip system.
- Conceptual Prototyping Collaborated with the innovation team to generate conceptual prototypes for new features and products.
- Supporting the Engineering team and ensuring effective implementation.
- Visual Data Representation: Collaborate with cybersecurity teams to translate data insights into visually compelling graphics. Design engaging and informative infographics and data visualizations to simplify complex concepts.
- Brand Guidelines provided occasional support to the Brand team by contributing to product design guidelines and company branding materials.
- Mentorship and Guidance for junior colleagues by understanding the design problems that need solving and offering Guidance and feedback to support their work.

#### **EXPERIENCE DESCRIPTION**



## **UX/UI Product Design & Architecture**

Scotia Bank

Working part of the Universal Lab team - supporting Scotiabank's mobile App. Designing wireframes and interactive prototypes for a facing iPad application that redefines the future of banking for self-service.



### UX/UI Research | Visual Design & Video Editing

Compass Group

Mayo Clinic, TJX, Companies, Toronto Zoo

Collaborate with business team members to define requirements and establish user goals, objectives, and success metrics to ensure product success. Design user-centered experiences through usability research and design thinking for mobile, tablet, web, and kiosk platforms. Include journey maps, personas, wireframes, UI elements, illustrations, iconography, and interactive kiosks. Occasionally assisting with video and sound editing for promos. Collaboration with engineering teams to understand the technical constraints. With exposure to Agile methodologies.



### **UI Interactive Designer & Illustrator**

1 01/2014 - 07/2014

Wizits Ltd Game Studio

Illustrating UI and iconography for game elements and story themes. Creating animations and video for publishing. Designing for a game that runs both on the web and mobile.



## Interactive Digital Designer & Illustraor

| 09/2012 - 03/2013

BWIN Party Digital Media and Entertainment

Producing conceptual designs for all Brand elements in the business. Considering localization for a copy that was translated and published in more than 22 languages worldwide. Choosing the appropriate style to agreed standards and time frames; ensuring that the creative produced of high quality and supports the Brand's guidelines.



### **Digital Designer**

Tesco Direct - Publishing

Working part of a major business transformation and re-launch, within the Web Publishing and Merchandising team. Designing web pages, banners, newsletters, icons, visual navigation and other online graphics and illustrations. Responsible for creating visual appeal for the new website, in departments such as Clothing, Beauty, Home, Technology, Gaming, Sports and more. Finding creative and innovative visual solutions, with designs that identifies with the target audience, supporting costumer journeys and meeting the Brand's guidelines.

## **SKILLS**



